africanews.com 2009-06-21

# AfricaNews - Privacy policy

## Privacy Policy

1.    Africa Interactive recognizes that its customers, visitors, users, and others who use Africa Interactive (collectively or individually "Users") value their privacy. This Privacy Policy details important information regarding the use and disclosure of User information collected on Africa Interactive. Africa Interactive provides this Privacy Policy to help you make an informed decision about whether to use or continue using Africa Interactive.

2.    This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and is subject to the Africa Interactive Terms & Conditions. Your use of Africa Interactive and any personal information you provide Africa Interactive remains subject to the terms of this Privacy Notice and our **[Terms& Conditions](http://www.africanews.com/site/page/terms_and_conditions)**.

3.    Please note that any content (including any text, photographs, graphics, video or audio) on any part of Africa Interactive becomes published content and is not considered personally identifiable information subject to this Privacy Policy.

 **The Information Africa Interactive Collects**

4.    User Provided Information: You provide certain personally identifiable information (such as your name and email address) to Africa Interactive when choosing to participate in various activities on Africa Interactive such as opening a profile, setting up a web log, submitting articles, uploading photos, uploading videos, posting messages in our forums or, entering contests or sweepstakes, taking advantage of promotions, responding to surveys, or subscribing to newsletters or other mailing lists.

5.    Cookies Information: When you visit Africa Interactive, we may send one or more cookies - a small text file containing a string of alphanumeric characters - to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser. Africa Interactive uses both session cookies and persistent cookies. A persistent cookie remains after you close your browser. Persistent cookies may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the site. Persistent cookies can be removed by following your web browser help file directions. A session cookie is temporary and disappears after you close your browser. You can reset your web browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some features of the Africa Interactive Sites may not function properly if the ability to accept cookies is disabled. 

6.    Log File Information: When you use Africa Interactive, our servers automatically record certain information that your web browser sends whenever you visit any website. These server logs may include information such as your web request, Internet Protocol ("IP") address, browser type, browser language, referring / exit pages and URLs, platform type, number of clicks, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed and the order of those pages, the amount of time spent on particular pages, the date and time of your request, and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your browser. 

7.    Clear GIFs Information: When you use Africa Interactive, we may employ "clear GIFs" (a.k.a. Web Beacons) which are used to track the online usage patterns of our Users anonymously (i.e., in a non-personally-identifiable manner). In addition, we may also use clear GIFs in HTML-based emails sent to our users to track which emails are opened by recipients.

 **The Way Africa Interactive Uses Information**

8.    If you submit personally identifiable information to Africa Interactive, then we use your personal information to operate, maintain, and provide to you the features and functionality of Africa Interactive. We will not make your personally identifiable information generally available to other users and/or any third parties except as provided for in article 25 of this privacy policy.

9.    Any personal information or content that you voluntarily disclose online (on discussion boards, in messages and chat areas, within your public profile page, etc.) becomes publicly available and can be collected and used by others. Africa Interactive and other Users can contact you through messages and comments. Any content that you submit to Africa Interactive may be redistributed through the internet and other media channels, and may be viewed by the general public.

10.    We do not use your email address or other personally identifiable information to send commercial or marketing messages without your consent or except as part of a specific program or feature for which you will have the ability to opt-in or opt-out. We may, however, use your email address without further consent for highlighting these opt-in or opt-out services (including a marketing message) or for other non-marketing or administrative purposes (such as notifying you of major Africa Interactive Site changes or for customer service purposes). 

11.    We use both your personally identifiable information and certain non-personally-identifiable information (such as anonymous User usage data, cookies, IP addresses, browser type, clickstream data, etc.) to improve the quality and design of Africa Interactive and to create new features, promotions, functionality, and services by storing, tracking, and analyzing User preferences and trends. 

12.    We use cookies, clear gifs, and log file information to: 

\- remember information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit Africa Interactive;   
\- provide custom, personalized content and information;   
\- monitor the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns;   
\- monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors, pages viewed, etc.; a  
\- track your entries, submissions, and status in promotions, sweepstakes, and contests. 

**When Africa Interactive Discloses Information**

13.    We provide personally identifiable information and non-personally-identifiable information to our subsidiaries, affiliated companies, or other businesses or persons for the purpose of processing such information on our behalf. We require that these parties agree to process such information in compliance with our privacy policy, and we take reasonable efforts to limit their use of such information and to use other appropriate confidentiality and security measures. 

14.    We do not share your personally identifiable information (such as name or email address) with other, third-party companies for their commercial or marketing use without your consent or except as part of a specific program or feature for which you will have the ability to opt-in or opt-out. 

15.    We do share non-personally-identifiable information (such as anonymous User usage data, referring / exit pages and URLs, platform types, number of clicks, etc.) with interested third-parties to assist them in understanding the usage patterns for certain content, services, advertisements, promotions, and/or functionality on Africa Interactive. 

16.    We may release personally identifiable information and/or non-personally-identifiable information if required to do so by law, or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with or respond to a court order, subpoena, or search warrant. 

17.    Africa Interactive also reserves the right to disclose personally identifiable information and/or non-personally-identifiable information that Africa Interactive believes, in good faith, is appropriate or necessary to enforce our Terms & Conditions, take precautions against liability, to investigate and defend itself against any third-party claims or allegations, to assist government enforcement agencies, to protect the security or integrity of our web site, and to protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Africa Interactive, our Users or others. 

**Your Choices**

18.    You may, of course, decline to submit personally identifiable information through Africa Interactive, in which case Africa Interactive may not be able to provide certain services to you. You may update or correct your personal profile information and email preferences at any time by visiting your Personal Profile Page. Please note that content uploaded by Users to Africa Interactive cannot be removed and remain subject to our Terms & Conditions.

19.    You have the right to request that Africa Interactive provides information, e.g. about the personal data it processes or about the purposes of the processing of such data. You also have the right to request that Africa Interactive rectifies, erases or blocks the personal data (for example because of the incomplete or inaccurate nature of the data). To execute any of these requests please contact us at EMAILADRESS, ADRESS or PHONENUMBER.

20.    To protect your privacy and security, we take reasonable steps (such as requesting a unique password) to verify your identity before granting you profile access or making corrections. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your unique password and account information at all times.

21.    Please contact Africa Interactive with any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, your personal information, your consent, or your opt-in or opt-out choices.

 **Third-party Partners, Links to Other Sites**

22.    Africa Interactive works with other companies, called third-party ad servers or ad networks, to serve advertisements within the Africa Interactive Sites. These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to send, directly to your browser, the advertisements and links that appear on Africa Interactive. They automatically receive your IP address when this happens. They may also use other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons) to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and to personalize the advertising content you see.

23.    Africa Interactive does not provide any personally identifiable information to these third-party ad servers or ad networks without your consent or except as part of a specific program or feature for which you will have the ability to opt-in or opt-out. However, please note that if an advertiser asks Africa Interactive to show an advertisement to a certain audience (for example, men ages 18-34) or audience segment (for example, men ages 18-24 who have viewed certain channels of content) and you respond to that advertisement, the advertiser or ad-server may conclude that you fit the description of the audience they are trying to reach. The advertiser may also use information regarding your use of Africa Interactive, such as the number of times you viewed an ad (but not any personally identifiable information), to determine which ads to deliver to you.

24.    You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers or ad networks for more information on their practices and for instructions on how to opt-out of certain practices. Africa Interactive privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.

 **In the Event of Merger, Sale, or Bankruptcy**

25.    In the event that Africa Interactive is acquired by or merged with a third party entity, individual personal information may be transferred to the third party pursuant to such acquisition or merger. By accepting this Privacy Policy you agree, in any of these circumstances, to transfer or assign the information we have collected from our Users as part of such merger, acquisition, sale, or other change of control. In the unlikely event of our bankruptcy, insolvency, reorganization, receivership, or assignment for the benefit of creditors, or the application of laws or equitable principles affecting creditors' rights generally, we may not be able to control how your personal information is treated, transferred, or used.

 **Changes and updates to this Privacy Policy**

26.    This Privacy Policy may be revised periodically. Please revisit this page to stay aware of any changes. In general, we only use your personal information in the manner described in the Privacy Policy in effect when we received the personal information you provided. Your continued use of the Africa Interactive Sites constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Policy and any future revisions.  
Each version of this policy can be identified by its effective date at the top of the page.  
 **  
General**

27.    If any of these terms are determined to be illegal, invalid or otherwise unenforceable by reason of the laws of any state or country in which these terms are intended to be effective, then to the extent and within the jurisdiction in which that term is illegal, invalid or unenforceable, it shall be severed and deleted from these terms and the remaining terms shall survive, remain in full force and effect and continue to be binding and enforceable.  
 **  
Jurisdiction and applicable law**

28.    These terms shall be construed in accordance with and shall exclusively be governed by Netherlands law. The competent court of Haarlem, The Netherlands, shall have exclusive jurisdiction in respect of any relevant proceedings. In case you are not domiciled in The Netherlands, local mandatory law may apply.
